Look, I had second thoughts, really,
انظروا، كنت أعيد النظر، حقيقة،
about whether I could talk about this
فيما هل يمكنني التكلم عن موضوع كهذا
to such a vital and alive audience as you guys.
لجمهور حيوي وفي مثل نشاطكم.
Then I remembered the quote from Gloria Steinem,
عندها تذكرت اقتباس من قلوريا ستاينم،
which goes,
والتي تقول
"The truth will set you free,
"الحقيقة ستحررك،
but first it will piss you off." (Laughter)
لكن في البداية ستغضبك". (ضحك)
So -- (Laughter)
لذا -- (ضحك)
So with that in mind, I'm going to set about
لذا وبأخذ ذلك في الاعتبار، سأبدأ بتحريركم من موضوع
trying to do those things here,
محاولا فعل هذه الاشياء هنا،
and talk about dying in the 21st century.
و أتكلم عن الموت في القرن 21.
Now the first thing that will piss you off, undoubtedly,
الآن أول شيء سيغضبكم، بلا شك،
is that all of us are, in fact, going to die
هو أن كلنا، في الحقيقة سنموت
in the 21st century.
في القرن 21.
There will be no exceptions to that.
لا يوجد أي استثناء لهذا.
There are, apparently, about one in eight of you
يوجد، كما يبدو، واحد من ثمانية منكم
who think you're immortal, on surveys, but --
من يعتقد أنه خالد، في دراسات، لكن --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Unfortunately, that isn't going to happen.
لسوء الحظ، ذلك لن يحدث.
While I give this talk, in the next 10 minutes,
بينما أعطي هذا الخطاب، خلال العشر دقائق،
a hundred million of my cells will die,
مئة مليون من خلاياي ستموت،
and over the course of today, 2,000 of my brain cells
و ما يزيد عن 2.000 خلية من خلايا دماغي، خلال مسار اليوم،
will die and never come back,
ستموت و لن تعود،
so you could argue that the dying process
لذا يمكنك مناقشة أن عملية الموت
starts pretty early in the piece.
تبدأ في فترة مبكرة.
Anyway, the second thing I want to say about dying in the
على أي حال، ثاني شيء أريد قوله عن الموت في
21st century, apart from it's going to happen to everybody,
القرن 21، بعيداً عن أنها ستحدث للجميع،
is it's shaping up to be a bit of a train wreck
أنها بدأت بالتشكل لتصبح قليلا مثل حطام قطار
for most of us,
لمعظمنا،
unless we do something to try and reclaim this process
مالم نفعل شيئاً لاستصلاح هذه العملية
from the rather inexorable trajectory that it's currently on.
من المسار المتعذر تغييره الذي هو يعمل حالياً
So there you go. That's the truth.
وها أنت ترى، هذه الحقيقة.
No doubt that will piss you off, and now let's see
بلا شك ستغضبك، و الآن لنرى
whether we can set you free. I don't promise anything.
هل سنستطيع تحريركم. لا أعد بشيء.
Now, as you heard in the intro, I work in intensive care,
حالياً، كما سمعتم في التقديم، أعمل في العناية المركزة،
and I think I've kind of lived through the heyday
و أعتقد أني عشت خلال الذروة
of intensive care. It's been a ride, man.
من العناية المركزة. كانت رحلة، يارجل.
This has been fantastic.
لقد كان هذا رائعاً.
We have machines that go ping.
لدينا آلات تصدر الصوت "بينق".
There's many of them up there.
يوجد الكثير منها هناك.
And we have some wizard technology which I think
و لدينا بعض التقنيات السحرية و التي أعتقد
has worked really well, and over the course of the time
أنها عملت بشكل جيد جداً، وخلال مرور الزمن
I've worked in intensive care, the death rate
الذي عملت فيه في العناية المركزة، نسبة الموت
for males in Australia has halved,
للذكور في أستراليا قد انخفضت إلى النصف،
and intensive care has had something to do with that.
و العناية المركزة لها دور في ذلك.
Certainly, a lot of the technologies that we use
بالتأكيد، الكثير من التقنيات التي نستخدمها
have got something to do with that.
لها دور في ذلك.
So we have had tremendous success, and we kind of
لذا لدينا نجاح هائل، و بطريقة ما
got caught up in our own success quite a bit,
وعلقنا في نجاحنا لمدة بسيطة،
and we started using expressions like "lifesaving."
و بدأنا نستخدم عبارات مثل "إنقاذ الحياة"
I really apologize to everybody for doing that,
أنا حقاً أعتذر للجميع لفعل هذا،
because obviously, we don't.
لأننا كما يبدو، لانفعل.
What we do is prolong people's lives,
ما نفعله هو أننا نمد في حياة البشر،
and delay death,
و نؤخر الموت،
and redirect death, but we can't, strictly speaking,
ونعيد توجيه الموت، لكننا لانستطيع، بمعنى دقيق للكلمة،
save lives on any sort of permanent basis.
أن ننقذ حياة الناس بأي شكل دائم.
And what's really happened over the period of time
وما حدث خلال المدة الطويلة من الزمن
that I've been working in intensive care is that
التي عملت خلالها في العناية المركزة هو
the people whose lives we started saving back in the '70s,
أن حياة الأشخاص الذين بدأنا إنقاذها في السبعينات،
'80s, and '90s, are now coming to die in the 21st century
والثمانينات، والتسعينات، هم الآن سيموتون في القرن ال21
of diseases that we no longer have the answers to
من أمراض لم يعد لدينا إجابات لها
in quite the way we did then.
بالطريقة التي فعلنا في السابق.
So what's happening now is there's been a big shift
إذا مايحدث الآن هو أن حصل تحول كبير
in the way that people die,
في الطريقة التي يموت بها الناس،
and most of what they're dying of now isn't as amenable
و معظم مايموت به الناس الآن لا يمكن اخضاعها
to what we can do as what it used to be like
لما نستطيع فعله كالسابق
when I was doing this in the '80s and '90s.
عندما كنت أفعل ذلك في الثمانينات و التسعينات.
So we kind of got a bit caught up with this,
اذا نحن بطريقة ما علقنا مع هذا،
and we haven't really squared with you guys about
و لم نكن معكم عادلين فيما يخص
what's really happening now, and it's about time we did.
ما يحدث في الواقع الآن، و حان الوقت أن نفعل
I kind of woke up to this bit in the late '90s
بطريقة ما تيقظت للتالي في آواخر التسعينات
when I met this guy.
عندما تعرفت على ذلك الرجل.
This guy is called Jim, Jim Smith, and he looked like this.
الرجل يدعى جيم، جيم سميث، وبدا كهذا.
I was called down to the ward to see him.
تم استدعائي للجناح لرؤيته.
His is the little hand.
وهذه يده الصغيرة.
by a respiratory physician.
عن طريق طبيب الصدرية
He said, "Look, there's a guy down here.
وقال، أنظر يوجد رجل هنا
He's got pneumonia,
لديه التهاب رئوي،
and he looks like he needs intensive care.
و يبدو انه يحتاج إلى عناية مركزة.
His daughter's here and she wants everything possible
ابنته هنا وتريد كل شيء ممكن
to be done."
أن يفعل"
Which is a familiar phrase to us.
وهي عبارة مألوفة لنا
So I go down to the ward and see Jim,
لذا ذهبت للجناح لرؤية جيم،
and his skin his translucent like this.
وجلده شفاف هكذا.
You can see his bones through the skin.
بإمكانك رؤية عظامه من خلال الجلد.
He's very, very thin,
هو نحيف جداً، جداً،
and he is, indeed, very sick with pneumonia,
وهو بالفعل ، جداً مريض بالإلتهاب الرئوي،
and he's too sick to talk to me,
و هو جداً مريض بحيث لا يستطيع الكلام معي،
so I talk to his daughter Kathleen, and I say to her,
لذا كلمت ابنته كاثلين، و قلت لها،
"Did you and Jim ever talk about
"هل تحدثتي مع جيم عن
what you would want done
ماذا قد تريدون أن يحصل
if he ended up in this kind of situation?"
في حال حصل مثل هذا الموقف؟"
And she looked at me and said, "No, of course not!"
ونظرت إلي و قالت، "لا، بالتأكيد لم نفعل!"
I thought, "Okay. Take this steady."
فكرت في داخلي،"طيب، تناولي الموضوع بهدوء."
And I got talking to her, and after a while, she said to me,
و بدأت أكلمها، وبعد مدة، قالت لي،
"You know, we always thought there'd be time."
"هل تعرف، كنا دائما نفكر سيكون هناك وقت."
Jim was 94. (Laughter)
جيم عمره 94.(ضحك)
And I realized that something wasn't happening here.
و استنتجت شيئاً لم يكن يحدث هنا.
There wasn't this dialogue going on
لم يوجد ذلك الحوار
that I imagined was happening.
الذي تخيلت أنه يحدث.
So a group of us started doing survey work,
لذا بدأت مجموعة منا بعمل دراسات،
and we looked at four and a half thousand nursing home
ونظرنا إلى أربعة ونصف ألف سكان تمريض منزلي
residents in Newcastle, in the Newcastle area,
في نيوكاسل، في منطقة نيوكاسل،
and discovered that only one in a hundred of them
و اكتشفنا انه فقط واحد من المئة منهم
had a plan about what to do when their hearts stopped beating.
لديه خطة عن ماذا يفعل عندما يتوقف قلبهم عن النبض.
One in a hundred.
واحد من المئة.
And only one in 500 of them had plan about what to do
و فقط واحد من 500 منهم قد خطط في ماذا
if they became seriously ill.
سيحصل إذا مرضوا مرضا خطيرا
And I realized, of course, this dialogue
و أدركت، بالتأكيد، هذا الحوار
is definitely not occurring in the public at large.
لم يكن يحدث في العموم بشكل كبير.
Now, I work in acute care.
الآن، أعمل في عناية الحالات الخطرة.
This is John Hunter Hospital.
هذا مشفى جون هنتر.
And I thought, surely, we do better than that.
وفكرت، من المؤكد نحن نفكر بشكل أفضل من هذا.
So a colleague of mine from nursing called Lisa Shaw and I
لذا زميلة لي من التمريض تدعى ليزا شو و أنا
went through hundreds and hundreds of sets of notes
مررنا على مئات و مئات من المجموعات من الملاحظات
in the medical records department
في قسم السجلات الطبية
looking at whether there was any sign at all
نبحث عن ما إذا وجد أي إشارة على الإطلاق
that anybody had had any conversation about
أن هناك من أجرى مثل هذا الحوار عن
what might happen to them if the treatment they were
ماذا قد يحصل لهم إذا كان العلاج الذي
receiving was unsuccessful to the point that they would die.
يتلقونه غير ناجح للنقطة التي قد يموتون فيها.
And we didn't find a single record of any preference
ولم نجد أي سجل لأي رأي
about goals, treatments or outcomes from any
عن الأهداف، العلاجات أو النتائج من أي
of the sets of notes initiated by a doctor or by a patient.
من مجموعات الملاحظات منشأة من قبل الطبيب أو المريض.
So we started to realize
لذا بدأنا ندرك
that we had a problem,
أن لدينا مشكلة،
and the problem is more serious because of this.
و المشكلة أكثر خطورة بسبب هذا.
What we know is that obviously we are all going to die,
مانعلمه هو أننا بالتأكيد جميعنا سنموت،
but how we die is actually really important,
لكن كيف سنموت هو فعلياً أكثر أهمية،
obviously not just to us, but also to how that
بالتأكيد ليس لنا فقط، لكن أيضاً لكيف
features in the lives of all the people who live on afterwards.
يؤثرفي حياة جميع الأشخاص الذين يعيشون بعدنا.
How we die lives on in the minds of everybody
كيف نموت نعيش في عقول الجميع
who survives us, and
من ينقذوننا، و
the stress created in families by dying is enormous,
وضخامة الضغط الناشئ في العوائل من الموت
and in fact you get seven times as much stress by dying
وفي الحقيقة يتضاعف الضغط سبع مرات من الموت
in intensive care as by dying just about anywhere else,
في العناية المركزة أثر من الموت في أي مكان آخر،
so dying in intensive care is not your top option
لذا فإن الموت في العناية المركزة ليس خيارك الأفضل
if you've got a choice.
إذا كان لك الإختيار
And, if that wasn't bad enough, of course,
و إذا لم يكن ذلك سيء بما بكفي، بالتأكيد،
all of this is rapidly progressing towards the fact that
كل هذا التقدم السريع باتجاه حقيقة أنه
many of you, in fact, about one in 10 of you at this point,
العديد منكم، في الحقيقة، حوالي واحد من العشرة منكم حتى هذه النقطة،
will die in intensive care.
سيموت في العناية المركزة.
In the U.S., it's one in five.
في الولايات المتحدة، واحد من خمسة.
In Miami, it's three out of five people die in intensive care.
في ميامي، ثلاثة من خمسة أشخاص سيموتون في العناية المركزة.
So this is the sort of momentum
لذا هذا النوع من الكميات
that we've got at the moment.
التي لدينا حالياً.
The reason why this is all happening is due to this,
السبب لحصول كل هذا ،
and I do have to take you through what this is about.
ويجب علي أن أخذكم خلال عن ماذا نتكلم
These are the four ways to go.
يوجد أربع طرق
So one of these will happen to all of us.
واحد من هذه ستحدث لنا كلنا.
The ones you may know most about are the ones
الطريقة التي تعرفونها أكثر هي
that are becoming increasingly of historical interest:
التي أصبحت ذات أهمية تاريخية:
sudden death.
الموت الفجأة.
It's quite likely in an audience this size
من المحتمل جداً في جمهور بهذا الحجم
this won't happen to anybody here.
هذا لن يحدث لأي شخص هنا.
Sudden death has become very rare.
الموت الفجأة أصبح نادر جداً.
The death of Little Nell and Cordelia and all that sort of stuff
الموت لنيلا الصغيرة وكورديليا وكل ذلك
just doesn't happen anymore.
لم يعد يحدث الآن
The dying process of those with terminal illness
عملية الموت لهؤلاء المصابين بأمراض مميته
that we've just seen
الذين كنا قد رأيناهم
occurs to younger people.
تحدث لناس الأصغر سناً
By the time you've reached 80, this is unlikely to happen to you.
عندما تصل ل80، يستبعد أن يحدث لك ذلك.
Only one in 10 people who are over 80 will die of cancer.
فقط واحد من عشرة أشخاص فوق الثمانين سيموتون من السرطان.
The big growth industry are these.
النمو الكبير للصناعة
What you die of is increasing organ failure,
ما نموت منه هو فشل عضوي متزايد،
with your respiratory, cardiac, renal,
مع تنفسك، قلبي، كلوي،
whatever organs packing up. Each of these
أي من الأعضاء يحتمل الكثير من الأعباء. كل من هذه
would be an admission to an acute care hospital,
ستكون كبطاقة دخول لمشفى العناية بالحالات الخطرة،
at the end of which, or at some point during which,
في النهاية لذلك، أو خلال أي نقطة خلال ذلك،
somebody says, enough is enough, and we stop.
شخص ما يقول، هذا كافي، ونتوقف.
And this one's the biggest growth industry of all,
أما بانسبة لهذا فهو أكبر قطاع ينمو ،
and at least six out of 10 of the people in this room
وعلى الأقل ستة من عشرة من الأشخاص في هذه المكان
will die in this form, which is
سيموت بهذه الطريقة، وهي
the dwindling of capacity
تناقص في الكفاءة
with increasing frailty,
مع تزايد في الضعف،
and frailty's an inevitable part of aging,
و الضعف جزء لا مفر منه من الشيخوخة،
and increasing frailty is in fact the main thing
و التزايد في الضعف هو في الحقيقة الشيء الرئيسي
that people die of now,
الذي يموت منه الناس الآن،
and the last few years, or the last year of your life
و خلال السنوات القليلة الماضية، أو خلال السنة الأخيرة من حياتك
is spent with a great deal of disability, unfortunately.
تقضى بقدر كبير من الإعاقة، لسوء الحظ.
Enjoying it so far? (Laughs)
هل استمتعتم لحد الآن؟ (ضحك)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Sorry, I just feel such a, I feel such a Cassandra here.
آسف، فقط أشعر كأني، كاسندرا .
What can I say that's positive? What's positive is
ماهو الشيء الإيجابي الذي أستطيع قول؟ ماهو إيجابي
that this is happening at very great age, now.
أن هذا يحدث في عمر كبير جداً، حالياً
We are all, most of us, living to reach this point.
نحن جميعاً، نعيش لنصل لتلك النقطة.
You know, historically, we didn't do that.
تعرفون، تاريخياً، لم يحصل ذلك.
This is what happens to you
هذا مايحدث لك
when you live to be a great age,
عندما تعيش إلى عمر كبير،
and unfortunately, increasing longevity does mean
و لسوء الحظ، زيادة طول العمر تعني
more old age, not more youth.
عمر كبير أكثر، ليس شباب أكثر.
I'm sorry to say that. (Laughter)
أعتذر عن قول ذلك. (ضحك)
What we did, anyway, look, what we did,
مافعلناه، على أي حال، انظروا ماذا فعلنا،
we didn't just take this lying down
لم نأخذ هذا الرسم فقط
at John Hunter Hospital and elsewhere.
في مشفى جون هنتر و أماكن أخرى.
We've started a whole series of projects
بحن بدأنا سلسلة كاملة من المشاريع
to try and look about whether we could, in fact, involve
لمحاولة النظر فيما هل يمكننا، في الحقيقة، تضمين
people much more in the way that things happen to them.
الناس أكثر بكثير في الطريقة التي ستحدث بها الأمور لهم.
But we realized, of course, that we are dealing
لكننا أدركنا، بالتأكيد، أننا نتعامل
with cultural issues,
مع مشاكل حضارية،
and this is, I love this Klimt painting,
وهذه، أحب لوحة كليمت هذه
because the more you look at it, the more you kind of get
لأنه كلما نظرت لها أكثر، كلما فهمت
the whole issue that's going on here,
المشكلة ككل التي تحدث هنا،
which is clearly the separation of death from the living,
وهي بوضوح انفصال الموت عن الحياة،
and the fear — Like, if you actually look,
والخوف ــــ مثل، لو نظرتم فعلاً
there's one woman there
هناك امرأة واحدة هناك
who has her eyes open.
عيناها مفتوحة.
She's the one he's looking at,
هي الفرد الذي ينظر له،
and [she's] the one he's coming for. Can you see that?
وهي التي سيأتي لها. هل تستطيعون رؤية ذلك؟
She looks terrified.
تبدو مرتعبة.
It's an amazing picture.
إنها صورة رائعة.
Anyway, we had a major cultural issue.
على أي حال، عانينا من مشاكل حضارية جوهرية
Clearly, people didn't want us to talk about death,
بكل وضوح، الناس لم يريدونا أن نتكلم عن الموت،
or, we thought that.
أو، اعتقدنا ذلك.
So with loads of funding from the Federal Government
لذا مع الكثير من الدعم المالي من الحكومة الفدرالية
and the local Health Service, we introduced a thing
و الخدمات الصحية المحلية، قدمنا شيء
at John Hunter called Respecting Patient Choices.
في جون هنتر يدعى احترام اختيارات المريض.
We trained hundreds of people to go to the wards
قمنا بتدريب المئات من الأشخاص للذهاب إلى الأجنحة
and talk to people about the fact that they would die,
و تكلمنا مع الأشخاص عن حقيقة أنهم قد يموتون،
and what would they prefer under those circumstances.
و ماذا قد يفضلون في حال خضوعهم لمثل هذه الظروف
They loved it. The families and the patients, they loved it.
أحبوها. العوائل و المرضى، أحبوها.
Ninety-eight percent of people really thought
تسعة وثمانين بالمئة ظنوا حقيقة
this just should have been normal practice,
أن هذا يجب أن يكون إجراء روتيني،
and that this is how things should work.
و أنه هكذا يجب أن تتم الأمور.
And when they expressed wishes,
وعندما عبروا عن أمانيهم،
all of those wishes came true, as it were.
جميع أمانيهم تحققت، مثل ماهي.
We were able to make that happen for them.
استطعنا أن نحقق لهم ذلك.
But then, when the funding ran out,
لكن عندها، عندما انتهى من التمويل،
we went back to look six months later,
عدنا إلى ستة اشهر قادمة،
and everybody had stopped again,
والجميع توقفوا مرة أخرى،
and nobody was having these conversations anymore.
ولم يعد أحد يجري هذه الحوارات مرة أخرى.
So that was really kind of heartbreaking for us,
لذا ذلك كسر قلوبنا
because we thought this was going to really take off.
لأننا اعتقدنا أن هذا سيستمر.
The cultural issue had reasserted itself.
المشكلة الحضارية فرضت نفسها من جديد.
So here's the pitch:
لذا اليكم النغمة:
I think it's important that we don't just get on this freeway
أعتقد أنه من المهم أن لا نصل لهذا بالطريق السريع
to ICU without thinking hard about whether or not
إلى وحدة العناية المركزة بدون تفكير فيما
that's where we all want to end up,
هل نريد أن ننتهي بهذه الطريقة او لا،
particularly as we become older and increasingly frail
بالتحديد عندما نصبح أكبر و يزداد ضعفنا
and ICU has less and less and less to offer us.
و وحدة العناية المركزة يصبح لديها القليل والقليل لتقدمه لنا.
There has to be a little side road
يجب أن يوجد طريق جانبي صغير
off there for people who don't want to go on that track.
للأشخاص الذين لايريدون أن يمضوا بذلك الطريق.
And I have one small idea,
ولدي فكرة صغيرة بسيطة،
and one big idea about what could happen.
و فكرة أخرى كبيرة عما يمكن أن يحدث.
And this is the small idea.
وهذه الفكرة الصغيرة.
The small idea is, let's all of us
الفكرة الصغيرة، جميعنا فل
engage more with this in the way that Jason has illustrated.
نرتبط أكثر بهذا بالطريقة التي شرحها جايسون.
Why can't we have these kinds of conversations
لما لا نستطيع إجراء مثل هذه الحوارات
with our own elders
مع شيوخنا
and people who might be approaching this?
و مع الأشخاص الذين قد يصلون لهذه المرحلة؟
There are a couple of things you can do.
يوجد عدة أشياء يمكنكم عملها.
One of them is, you can,
واحد منها، بإمكانكم،
just ask this simple question. This question never fails.
فقط طرح سؤال بسيط. هذا السؤال لن يفشل أبداً.
"In the event that you became too sick to speak for yourself,
"في الحدث الذي تصبح فيه جداً مريض لدرجة أنك لن تستطيع أن تتكلم عن نفسك،
who would you like to speak for you?"
من تريد أن يتكلم عنك؟"
That's a really important question to ask people,
هذا سؤال مهم لسؤال الناس،
because giving people the control over who that is
لأن إعطاء الناس السيطرة على من يكون ذلك الشخص
produces an amazing outcome.
ينتج نتائج رائعة.
The second thing you can say is,
الشيء الثاني الذي تستطيع قوله،
"Have you spoken to that person
"هل تكلمت مع ذلك الشخص
about the things that are important to you
في الأشياء المهمة بالنسبة لك
so that we've got a better idea of what it is we can do?"
لنحصل على فكرة أفضل عما نستطيع فعله؟"
So that's the little idea.
إذا تلك هي الفكرة الصغيرة.
The big idea, I think, is more political.
الفكرة الكبيرة، أعتقد، أنها سياسية أكثر.
I think we have to get onto this.
أعتقد أنه يجب أن نأتي لهذا.
I suggested we should have Occupy Death.
أقترح أنه يجب علينا أن نحتل الموت.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
My wife said, "Yeah, right, sit-ins in the mortuary.
زوجتي قالت، "نعم، صحيح، نعتصم عند مستودعات الجثث.
Yeah, yeah. Sure." (Laughter)
نعم، نعم. بالتأكيد" (ضحك)
So that one didn't really run,
حتى لانهرب في الحقيقة،
but I was very struck by this.
لكن كنت حقاً مصدوم بهذا.
Now, I'm an aging hippie.
الآن، أنا عجوز هبي.
I don't know, I don't think I look like that anymore, but
لاأعلم، لاأظن أني لازلت أبدو كذلك لكن
I had, two of my kids were born at home in the '80s
اثنان من أطفالي ولدوا في المنزل في الثمانينات
when home birth was a big thing, and we baby boomers
عندما كانت الولادة المنزلية شيء كبير، ونحن مولدون للأطفال
are used to taking charge of the situation,
اعتدنا أن نسيطر على الموقف،
so if you just replace all these words of birth,
لذا اذا استطعت أن تبدل كل هذه الكلمات من الولادة
I like "Peace, Love, Natural Death" as an option.
أحب "السلام، الحب، الموت الطبيعي" كخيار.
I do think we have to get political
أنا أعتقد أنه يجب ان نكون سياسيين
and start to reclaim this process from
ونبدأ بإستعادة هذه العملية من
the medicalized model in which it's going.
النموذج الطبي كما يحدث حالياً.
Now, listen, that sounds like a pitch for euthanasia.
الآن، اسمعوا، تبدو هذه كنغمة للقتل الرحيم
I want to make it absolutely crystal clear to you all,
أريد أن أجعلها واضحة كوضوح الكرستال لكم كلكم،
I hate euthanasia. I think it's a sideshow.
أكره القتل الرحيم. أعتقد أنه بديل جانبي.
I don't think euthanasia matters.
لاأعتقد أن القتل الرحيم يهم.
I actually think that,
أعتقد أنه،
in places like Oregon,
في أماكن مثل أوريغون،
where you can have physician-assisted suicide,
حيث يمكنك الحصول على طبيب-مساعد للانتحار،
you take a poisonous dose of stuff,
تأخذ جرعة سامة من الأشياء،
only half a percent of people ever do that.
فقط نصف بالمئة فعلوا ذلك.
I'm more interested in what happens to the 99.5 percent
أنا أكثر اهتمام بما يحدث لل99.5 الباقين
of people who don't want to do that.
من الناس الذين لايريدون فعل ذلك.
I think most people don't want to be dead,
أعتقد معظم الناس لايريدون أن يموتوا،
but I do think most people want to have some control
لكن أعتقد أن معظم الأشخاص يريدون بعض السيطرة
over how their dying process proceeds.
على كيفية حدوث عملية الموت.
So I'm an opponent of euthanasia,
لذا أنا ضد القتل الرحيم،
but I do think we have to give people back some control.
لكن أعتقد أنه يجب ان نعطي الأشخاص بعض من السيطرة.
It deprives euthanasia of its oxygen supply.
تحرم القتل الرحيم من مزودات الأكسجين
I think we should be looking at stopping
أظن أنه يجب أن ننظر للتوقف
the want for euthanasia,
في الرغبة في القتل الرحيم،
not for making it illegal or legal or worrying about it at all.
ليس لجعله قانوني أو غير قانوني أو القلق بشأنه على الإطلاق.
This is a quote from Dame Cicely Saunders,
هذا اقتباس من دايم سيسلي ساوندرس،
whom I met when I was a medical student.
التي تعرفت عليها عندما كنت طالب بكلية الطب.
She founded the hospice movement.
لقد أسست حركة الدير
And she said, "You matter because you are,
و قالت، "أنت تهم لأنك أنت،
and you matter to the last moment of your life."
و أنت تهم إلى آخر لحظة في حياتك"
And I firmly believe that
و أعتقد بشكل صارم أنها
that's the message that we have to carry forward.
هذه الرسالة التي يجب أن نحملها للأمام.
Thank you. (Applause)
شكراً لكم. (تصفيق)